hello in this video I will be explaining
to you an interesting gitlab server side
request for the rev owner ability that
was reported in hacker 1 and was
rewarded $5.00 first let's remind what
the SS Arab vulnerability is and what is
impact it occurs when an attacker can
force the server to perform a request to
a specified by him location but the sole
functionality does not mean it's
vulnerable
it becomes vulnerable when the attacker
can also request the addresses from
internal network or the local ones but
github has a bug bounty program on
hacker 1 since 2014 and they have
already resolved over 500 reports so you
may be thinking how has it happened that
it's still vulnerable to this attack in
2019 so good lab had a protection that
was supposed to prevent this type of
attacks there is a class URL blocker
that has protections against local host
and local network addresses so right now
we are inside the function called
validate and the interesting part is
here what it makes the DNS query and
returns the IP address resolved from the
domain provided by user and later all
these validations happen on the address
returned by the DNS server and when
these validations pass then get lab
decides that this URL is safe and a nice
TTP request can be made and for this
purpose and HTT part again is used but
before making an actual HTTP request it
makes a second DNS query so here we have
to notice that the domain can be
completely controlled by the attacker
and he can set up the DNS server that it
responds with a different IP address in
response to each query this type of
attack is called time of check time of
use and its use is not limited to a
seraphs
it occurs when the attacker is able to
cause the validating function and the
executing function to process different
inputs and in this example it is
achieved by the DNS server returning a
valid IP address on the first query and
then the local IP on the second
impact of this vulnerability is high
because it allowed the attacker to
request a Google Cloud metadata endpoint
for example and take over the whole
server an interesting part here is that
this report was first marked as
duplicate but later the gate lab team
have decided to work the reporter with a
5,000 pound T because it helped them to
realize that the attacker could obtain a
DCP token without the header so let's
see how they have fixed this
vulnerability so the validate function
no longer returns true or false but now
it returns a URI and a hostname and
hostname is only used to validate the
SSL certificate but the actual HTTP
request is made to the IP address
returned by the first DNS query it
allows to avoid doing the second DNS
query I hope you now understand the
vulnerability better if you have leave a
like and a subscription and for now
thank you